window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Theory_of_Computation - Theory_of_Computation — Slot 19 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Theory_of_Computation — Slot 19",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following statements is false? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1996)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The Halting Problem of Turing machines is undecidable</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Determining whether a context-free grammar is ambiguous is undecidable</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Given two arbitrary context-free grammars \\(G_1\\) and \\(G_2\\)it is undecidable whether \\(L(G_1) = L(G_2)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Given two regular grammars \\(G_1\\) and \\(G_2\\) it is undecidable whether \\(L(G_1) = L(G_2)\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Given two regular grammars \\(G_1\\) and \\(G_2\\) it is undecidable whether \\(L(G_1) = L(G_2)\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2713/gate1996-1-9\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Which two of the following four regular expressions are equivalent? (\\(\\varepsilon\\) is the empty string).<br>\n(i).   \\((00)^ * (\\varepsilon +0)\\)<br>\n(ii).  \\((00)^*\\)<br>\n(iii). \\(0^*\\)<br>\n(iv).  \\(0(00)^*\\)<br> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1996)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) and (ii)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) and (iii)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(i) and (iii)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>(iii) and (iv)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>(i) and (iii)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2712/gate1996-1-8\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Let \\(\\Sigma=\\left\\{0,1\\right\\}, L = \\Sigma^* \\text{ and } R=\\left\\{0^n1^n \\mid n \\gt 0\\right\\}\\) then the languages \\(L \\cup R\\) and R are respectively <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>regular, regular</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>not regular, regular</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>regular, not regular</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>not regular, not regular</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>regular, not regular</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2637/gate1995-2-24\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>A finite state machine with the following state table has a single input x and a single out z.<br>\n\\(\\begin{array}{|c|ll|}\\hline \\textbf{present state} &amp;\\textbf{next state, z} \\\\ &amp; \\text{x=1} &amp; \\text{x=0} \\\\\\hline \\text{A} &amp; \\text{D,0} &amp; \\text{B,0} \\\\\\hline \\text{B} &amp; \\text{B,1} &amp; \\text{C,1} \\\\\\hline \\text{C} &amp; \\text{B,0} &amp; \\text{D,1} \\\\\\hline \\text{D} &amp; \\text{B,1} &amp; \\text{C,0} \\\\\\hline \\end{array}\\)<br>If the initial state is unknown, then the shortest input sequence to reach the final state C is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>01</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>10</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>101</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>110</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>10</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2636/gate1995-2-23\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following definitions below generate the same language as \\(L\\), where \\(L=\\{x^ny^n \\text{ such that } n\\geq 1 \\}\\)?<br>\nI.   \\(E \\rightarrow xEy\\mid xy\\)<br>\nII.  \\(x y \\mid (x^+xyy^+)\\)<br>\nIII. \\(x^+y^+\\)<br> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I and II</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>II and III</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>I only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2632/gate1995-2-20\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Consider a grammar with the following productions<br>\n\\(S \\rightarrow a \\alpha b \\mid b \\alpha c \\mid aB\\)<br>\n\\(S \\rightarrow \\alpha S\\mid b\\)<br>\n\\(S \\rightarrow \\alpha b b\\mid ab\\)<br>\n\\(S \\alpha \\rightarrow bd b\\mid b\\)<br>\nThe above grammar is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Context free</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Regular</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Context sensitive</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>LR(k)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>LR(k)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2597/gate1995-1-10\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>In some programming language, an identifier is permitted to be a letter followed by any number of letters or digits. If L and D denote the sets of letters and digits respectively, which of the following expressions defines an identifier? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((L + D)^+\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((L.D)^*\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(L(L + D)^*\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L(L.D)^*\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(L(L + D)^*\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2596/gate1995-1-9-isro2017-13\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following features cannot be captured by context-free grammars? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Syntax of if-then-else statements</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Syntax of recursive procedures</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Whether a variable has been declared before its use</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Variable names of arbitrary length</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Whether a variable has been declared before its use</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2461/gate1994-1-18\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following conversions is not possible (algorithmically)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Regular grammar to context free grammar</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Non-deterministic FSA to deterministic FSA</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Non-deterministic PDA to deterministic PDA</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Non-deterministic Turing machine to deterministic Turing machine</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Non-deterministic PDA to deterministic PDA</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2459/gate1994-1-16\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following problem x . <br>\nGiven a Turing machine M over the input alphabet \\(\\Sigma\\), any state q of M.\nAnd a word w \\(\\in \\Sigma *\\)) does the computation of M on w visit the state q ?<br>\nWhich of the following statements about x is correct ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>x is decidable</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>x is undecidable but partially decidable</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>x is undecidable and not even partially decidable</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>x is not a decision problem</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>x is undecidable but partially decidable</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/725/gate2001-2-7#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following languages :<br>\nL1 = {ww| w\\(\\in\\) {a,b}*}<br>\nL2 = {w\\(w^{R}| \\) w\\(\\in\\) {a,b} *, \\(w^{R}\\) is the reverse of w} <br>\nL3 = {\\(0^{2i}\\)|  i is an integer}<br>\nL4 ={\\(0^{{i}^{2}}\\) | i is an integer} <br>\nWhich of the languages are regular ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only L1 and L2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only L2, L3 and L4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Only L3 and L4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Only L3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Only L3</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/724/gate2001-2-6#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Consider a DFA over \\(\\Sigma\\)= {a,b} accepting all strings which have number of a's divisible by 6 and number of b's divisible by 8. What is the minimum number of\nstates that the DFA will have ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>8</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>14</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>15</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>48</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>48</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/723/gate2001-2-5#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Given an arbitary non-deterministic finite automaton (NFA) with N states, the\nmaximum number of states in an equivalent minimized DFA is at least. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(N^{2}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(2^{N}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>2N</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>N!</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(2^{N}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/699/gate2001-1-6#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following statements true ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>If a language is context free it can be always be accepted by a deterministic\npush-down automaton.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The union of two context free language is context free.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The intersection of two context free language is context free</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The complement of a context free language is context free</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>The union of two context free language is context free.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/698/gate2001-1-5#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following two statements : <br>\nS1: {\\(0^{2n}|n\\geq 1|\\)} is a regular language <br>\nS2 : {\\(0^{m}1^{n}0^{m+n}|m\\geq 1 and n\\geq 1|\\)} is a regular language <br>\nWhich of the following statements is correct? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only S2 is correct</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both S1 and S2 are correct</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of S1 and S2 is correct</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/697/gate2001-1-4#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
